1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



Our First Citizens Honored Today



	(Anytown, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 23,1989</TIMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> is the day our country honors its first citizens.  This is called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Native American Day</TIMEX>.

	On this day, we think about those who lived here many years before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> was born.  For hundreds of years, Indians owned the rights to all the land in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.  They farmed it, and they raised their families on it.  They still do many good things for this country they love.

	The first time this day was honored was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May of 1916</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Redfox</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX> tribe thought of the idea.  He traveled 4,000 miles while sharing his idea with leaders of many states.  He even reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White House</ENAMEX> and talked to the President.

	The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> helped plan the first <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Native American Day</TIMEX>.  For many years, it was held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>.  Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, it was changed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 23</TIMEX>.

	<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, parades will be held.  The Indians will wear their most colorful costumes and dance and sing.  Above all, it is a time to think about the many good things Native Americans have done for this country.



1. Who traveled 4,000 miles to share an idea?



2.  What is another name for Native Americans?



3.  When was the first <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Native American Day</TIMEX> held?



4.  Where did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redfox</ENAMEX> go with his idea?



5.  Why is it a good idea to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Native American Day</TIMEX>?

