1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 1989</TIMEX>) - Attention video game lovers!  Have you ever spent hours putting quarters in machines like Pac Man?  Does the name "Donkey Kong" have a special meaning for you?

	If so, you will enjoy a new show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Moving Image Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Queens</ENAMEX>.  It has 50 of the most popular video games on display.

	The first video game was sold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>.  It was called Computer Space.  The next year, the game of Pong was sold.  It could be played on TV screens at home.  Players tried to score points by hitting a ball back and forth.

	Pac Man had lovable blob characters.  They were named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blinky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inky</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX>.  They would chase and be chased through a maze.

	One of the biggest video hits was Space Invaders.  Kids would play for so many hours that their muscles became sore.  Soon doctors were treating hundreds of cases of "Space Invaders wrist." All these games and more can be seen at the museum for the next five months.



1.  Who were the characters in Pac Man?



2.  What video game could be played on TV screens at home?



3. When was the first video game sold?



4.  Where are the video games being displayed?



5.  Why did some video game players have to see a doctor?

