1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



Watch Out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sears</ENAMEX>!



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Redwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September, 1889</TIMEX>) A man named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Sears</ENAMEX> has been playing a joke on shoppers.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sears</ENAMEX> likes to sell items by mail.  Not long ago, he ran an ad in some newspapers In small towns.  The ad showed a drawing of lovely furniture.  There was a sofa and two chairs.

	The ad said the furniture was for sale.  It said the pieces were made of fine metal frames and were beautiful to see.  The ad said that for a short time only, these chairs would be shipped to all who paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">95 cents</NUMEX>.

	This message sounded too good to be true.  Still, a lot of people sent in their money.  Imagine their surprise when they received the furniture.  The furniture was made for a doll house!  They were tiny pieces.

	Some people complained.  That's when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sears</ENAMEX> showed them the tiny print in his ad.

In very small letters, he had included the word "miniature." That means the furniture was not full size.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sears</ENAMEX> says he did this to get attention.



1.  Who played a joke on shoppers?



2.  What does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sears</ENAMEX> ad offer?



3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sears</ENAMEX> play this joke?



4.  Where is the word "miniature"?



5.  Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sears</ENAMEX> play this joke?

