1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



Secret Surprises England



(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ENGLAND</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July, 1865</TIMEX>) - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Barry</ENAMEX>, the famous army doctor, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>.  He has been well-known in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> for 50 years.  But shocking news has been learned since his death.  It seems Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> was really a woman!

	No one guessed the doctor's secret all those years.  Women are not allowed to serve as doctors.  It seems Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> hid the truth so she could practice her love of medicine.

	Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> finished her training in medicine at the young age of 15.  Then she began her many years in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">army</ENAMEX>.  She was often honored for her work.  One time, she risked her own life to treat wounded soldiers.  This happened at the Battle of Waterloo.  Her courage was rewarded.  She was put in charge of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">army</ENAMEX> doctors in the country.

	Over the years, she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>.  She treated the sick in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> and India.  No place was too far for her to travel.

	No one is sure of the doctor's real name.  One story says that she was born a princess.  But she was never allowed to grow up in the king's castle.  The story says she was not allowed to tell her true name and background.





1. Who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July of 1865</TIMEX>?



2. What was Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>'s secret?



3. When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Barry</ENAMEX> become a doctor?



4. Where did Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> treat wounded soldiers?



5. Why did Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> keep the secret?

