1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



First Dog Will Write Life Story



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15,1989</TIMEX>) - Someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION" STATUS="OPT">White House</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> is about to write a book.  No, it's not President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> or his wife.  It's their family dog, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX>.  It has been learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX> plans to write her life story and tell how she became "First Dog."

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX> was born on a Kentucky farm.  She is a two-year-old English springer spaniel.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX> has spent much of the past few years begging for table scraps from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> grandchildren.  Not long ago, she became a mother of six.  Her puppies have now grown old enough to leave home.

	Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX> had free time, she needed a hobby.  Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> thought that writing would be just the thing.  Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX>'s paws don't hold a pen very well, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has promised to write down the words for her.

	She will most likely share some <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION" STATUS="OPT">White House</ENAMEX> secrets.  Some think that Millie will tell what song the President likes to sing while he works in the Oval Office.  Others think she will tell about the time she saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s ghost.  It remains to be seen whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX> will be a dog-gone good writer.



1. Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX>?



2.  What is she going to do?



3.  When was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX> born?



4.  Where does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie</ENAMEX> live?



5.  Why will Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> help?

