1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



Football Catches On Fast







	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LATROBE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PA.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 4, 1895</TIMEX>) - The new game of football is catching on fast, and each month new teams are being formed.

	<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last night</TIMEX> was the first time that a football player was paid.  The man's name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Brallier</ENAMEX>, and he was paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> to take the place of someone who was hurt.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s team is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeannette Sports Club</ENAMEX>.  He is the quarterback.  The other team was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latrobe YMCA</ENAMEX>.  Even with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s paid help, his team lost 12-0.

	More and more colleges are starting football teams.  They travel many miles to play other good teams.  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day, 1894</TIMEX>, a college team from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chicago</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX> to play.

	The first football game between two schools took place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX>.  Then the manner of keeping score was different.  Each time a touchdown was made, the team would score one point.  The first team to reach six points would win.  A game lasted about one hour.

Now the rules have changed.  A touchdown is worth six points.





1.  Who was the first football player to be paid?



2. What was the name of this player's team?



3.  When was the first football game between two schools?



4.  Where did this story take place?



5. Why was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Brallier</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>?

