1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



Man Want To Build Space Machine



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7,1921</TIMEX>) - Some men have foolish ideas.  Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H. Goddard</ENAMEX>, for example.  He is causing a great deal of fuss these days.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> has a silly idea that he thinks will work. He says it is possible to make a machine that will fly in outer space.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> calls his machine a "rocket." He has never made one, but he has written about it.  He believes that someday a rocket can travel to the moon.

	It is true that a few years ago, people laughed at the idea that man could fly.  Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> Brothers flew the first airplane.  But a plane needs air to fly.  In outer space, there is no air.  Even an airplane can't work in outer space.  That is why everyone knows that a rocket certainly could not make the long trip.

	Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> keeps working on his idea.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>, he received a patent for his rocket. A patent is a piece of paper that gives the owner the right to make money from an idea. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> may have a patent, but he has yet to build a rocket and prove it can fly in space.

	 This newspaper thinks it's time that people like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> stop trying to fool the public. Most of the world's great machines have already been built.  Dreamers like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> should start building useful things that will help people.



1.  Who has a foolish idea?



2.  What is his idea?



3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> get a patent?



4.  Where does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goddard</ENAMEX> think his rocket could go?



5.  Why is this a silly idea?

