1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4





Disneyland Opens!



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ANAHEIM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CALIF.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24,1955</TIMEX>) - A giant, new park opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.  It is like no other place in the world.  It is called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX>, and it has a lot of fun rides, like roller coasters.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX> is the dream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Disney</ENAMEX>.  He wanted to build a place where the whole family could have fun together.

	Four areas make up the park. One is called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adventure Land</ENAMEX>. There you can ride on boats that take you through forests with wild-looking animals. Each boat is named for a famous river of the world. You can hop on the Nile Princess or the Amazon Belle.

	The second area is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fantasy Land</ENAMEX>. Here you can see ghosts in haunted houses without getting scared. It's all make-believe, but it looks real. 

	<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Frontier Land</ENAMEX> shows you what it was like to live in the Old West.  And, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tomorrow Land</ENAMEX> gives you an idea of what the future might be like.

	One of the best rides is the Matterhorn.  It is a roller coaster that takes you up and down a fake mountain.  The real <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Matterhorn</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Switzerland</ENAMEX>.







1. Who had a dream to build a family park?



2.  What are the names of the boats in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adventure Land</ENAMEX>?



3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX> open?



4.  Where would you see ghosts at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX>?



5.  Why is the Matterhorn one of the best rides?

