1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX> to Open Today



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BROOKLYN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24, 1883</TIMEX>) - The world's greatest bridge will open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester Arthur</ENAMEX> will be on hand to honor those who helped build the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX>.

	The public is welcome to see a display of fireworks at the bridge.  Six warships will fire their guns in a salute to the bridge.

	The man who has done the most to build this bridge will not be able to see the finished work.  His name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Roebling</ENAMEX>.  He has been the one in charge of the workers.  Eleven years ago, he had an accident while he was at work on the bridge.  A fire broke out and the smoke almost killed him.

	Since that time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roebling</ENAMEX> has been in a wheelchair.  But he has continued to work on the bridge, with help from his wife.  She has carried his written orders to the workers for him.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> will stop by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roebling</ENAMEX>'s home after the bridge opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to wish him well.



1. Who almost died building the bridge?



2. What is the name of the bridge?



3. When did the bridge open?



4. Where will President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> go after the bridge opens?



5. Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roebling</ENAMEX> almost die?

