1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> Attacks <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Ships!



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 7, 1941</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> has attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> sailors in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> an started a war!  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> dropped their bombs while many of our sailors slept aboard their ships early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

	At least 189 planes from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> dropped the bombs in the first attack.  One hour later, 171 more planes flew by and caused more damage.

	At least one ship has sunk.  About 2,300 men on board have died.  Another 85 ships are at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>.  Most of them have been heavily damaged.

	Besides the ships, 150 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> planes on the ground have been destroyed.

	While all this happened, a group of Japanese were at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION" STATUS="OPT">White House</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>.  They had told President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> they were there to discuss peace.

	Because of the attack, the President announce this morning that we are now at war with the Japanese.  It is a sad day for all Americans.



1.  Who attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> ships?



2.  What damage was done?



3.  When were the bombs dropped?



4.  Where did this attack take place?



5.  Why were the Japanese visiting with President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>?

