1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s-4



Doctor Continues to Find Cures



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">DENVER</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>) - Some people are never too old to work.  At age 80, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Sabin</ENAMEX> just won't slow down.

	Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabin</ENAMEX> has been called "the greatest woman scientist of her time." She has spent her life finding cures for sickness.

	<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabin</ENAMEX> found a new way to check for TB.  TB is a terrible illness.  It hurts the lungs and can lead to death.  Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabin</ENAMEX>'s test has cut the number of TB cases in half in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX>.

	When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence</ENAMEX> was young, she knew she wanted to be a doctor.  But she could not afford to go to school.  She worked for three years to save enough money.  Then she was one of the first women to attend a new school for doctors. It was called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX>.

	Over the years, she became well-known.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX> invited her dinner at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

	Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabin</ENAMEX> always finds a new cause.  She tells people that sickness can come from dirt.  She gets angry when she sees garbage lying around.  Garbage can cause diseases.

	Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabin</ENAMEX> won't quit until people know a lot more about how to stay in good health.



1.  Who is Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Sabin</ENAMEX>?



2.  What disease was cut in half because of her work?



3.  When will Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabin</ENAMEX> stop working?



4.  Where did she go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>?



5.  Why does Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabin</ENAMEX> get angry when she sees garbage lying around?

