1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W's 3

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> Returns Home!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Genoa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3, 1493</TIMEX>)- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Columbus</ENAMEX> came home to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  It was almost nine months after he sailed away to find a shortcut to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India</ENAMEX>.
	As he arrived, crowds cheered.  Few thought they would see him alive again.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> says he did find a strange, lovely land. He claims it is full of people with red skin.  He calls them Indians.
	But most map makers do not believe they are from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India</ENAMEX>.  Instead, they think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> found a new land.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> set sail last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.  He had three ships called the Nina, the Pinta, and the Santa Maria.  For two months, his ships were tossed by storms. The food supply was small.  Some men wanted to turn back.
	But on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 12</TIMEX>, they spotted land. They stayed on the new land for four months.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> says he wants to return to the new land to study its size.

1.  Who set sail for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India</ENAMEX>?

2.  What was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> trying to find?

3.  Where was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus’</ENAMEX> home?

4.  When did they spot land?

5.  Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbus</ENAMEX> want to return to the new land?
