1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s3

Shuttle Flies Through Space!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CAPE CANAVERAL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">FLORIDA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1981</TIMEX>)-Two men are flying through space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tonight</TIMEX>.  They are riding in a new type of spaceship.  It is called the space shuttle.
	The two men are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crippen</ENAMEX>.  They are very brave to be the first to ride in the shuttle.
	The space shuttle was launched, or shot, into space like spaceships before it.  But it can land like an airplane.  Never before could a spaceship return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> without splashing into the ocean.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crippen</ENAMEX> are pilots.  They have spent years training for these few days in space.  They will land in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX>.
	The best thing about the space shuttle is that it can be used again.  After it returns, it will be cleaned up and checked over.  Then it will be flown back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> on the top of an airplane.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crippen</ENAMEX> can talk to people as they circle the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.  They often joke about life in space.  But they are quite proud of their jobs.

1. Who are the men in space?

2.  What are they traveling in?

3.  When will they return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>?

4. Where are they traveling?

5. Why is the shuttle better than other spaceships?
