1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W's 3

New Movie Comes to Town!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KANSAS CITY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KANSAS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 13,1939</TIMEX>)-A new movie has come to town. It takes place in our state.  The movie is called "The Wizard of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oz</ENAMEX>."
	In the movie, a young girl named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> lives on a farm.  She longs to travel to a land "over the rainbow." Then a storm comes along.  The winds blow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> and her dog <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toto</ENAMEX> far away.  They land in a beautiful place.
	They meet a man made out of tin.  He is afraid he will rust if it rains. They also meet a lion who is scared of most things.
	A third friend is a scarecrow.  The scarecrow is made of straw.  He is afraid of just one thing - a lighted match.
	Together, they go in search of a wizard.  The wizard lives in a land called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oz</ENAMEX>.  Only the wizard can help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> get home again.
	A wicked witch wants to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>.  Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> ever find her way home again?  You'll have to see the movie to see what happens.

1.  Who is the young girl in the movie?

2.  What is the name of the movie?

3.  When was this movie first shown?

4.  Where does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> live?

5.  Why would the scarecrow fear a lighted match?
