1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s3

The King Gives Up His Throne!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LONDON</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>)-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> is about to have a new king.  The present king, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>, has said he will soon leave the throne.  He has been king only for one year.
	This has not happened in a thousand years.  Once a king is crowned, he rules all his life.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>'s brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, will become king.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>'s father was king until he died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.  Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> became king.
	It is said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> is giving up the throne to get married.  The woman who will be his wife is not from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX>.  She is not from a royal family, either.
	The king of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> rules over millions of people.  Many of them don't even live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX>.  Most of them live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> becomes king, he will bring his family with him.  He has two daughters.  Their names are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Rose</ENAMEX>.  Someday, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> will be queen.  There are no sons to take over the throne.

1. Who is the king who is giving up his throne?

2.  What is the reason he is giving up the throne?

3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> become king?

4.  Where do many people ruled by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> live?

5.  Why will <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> someday rule <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX>?
