1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W's 3

Miracle Boy!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BOSTON</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 15, 1986</TIMEX>)-A boy was riding his sled down a hill of snow.  Suddenly, he went too far.  The boy landed on a frozen pond.  The ice broke, and he sank into the water.
	The boy's father was scared.  He could not see his son.  He ran and got help.  By the time they found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>, he was frozen - He didn't look like he was alive.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> was rushed to the hospital. The doctors warmed his body a little bit at a time.  Slowly, he began to get warm.  The doctors were surprised that he was breathing.  Most people cannot live underwater for more than three minutes.
	<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> was well enough to go home.  The doctors call him a miracle boy.  They are trying to find out how he lived underwater for 30 minutes.
	The doctors think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>'s body got so cold that he didn't need much air.  He must have had his face near an air bubble.  He only breathed once or twice a minute underwater.


1.  Who warmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>'s body?

2.  What do the doctors call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>?

3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> go home?

4.  Where was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>'s face underwater?

5. Why do the doctors think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> didn't need much air?
