1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W's 3

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> Has A Birthday!


	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">DALLAS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TEXAS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1989</TIMEX>)-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX>, the doll, turns 30 years old in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.  It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> should be all grown up.  But she still looks like a teenager.  Since she is only a doll, she never has to look older.
	The first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll was made by a mother for her little girl.  Soon, she started making these dolls for other little girls.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> was not like other dolls.  She wore high heels and looked grown up.
	Over the years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> has had many looks.  Most of the dolls have blond hair and blue eyes.  But a few have brown hair.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> dolls always have long, lovely hair to comb.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> also has a younger sister named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scooter</ENAMEX>.  She has a lot of friends.  The oldest is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midge</ENAMEX>.  Her boyfriend's name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>.
	Almost no one can find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll that is 30 years old.  If you could find one, it would be worth a lot of money.


1. Who is celebrating her 30th birthday?

2.  What is her sister's name?

3.  When was the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll made?

4. Where might you look to find an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll?

5. Why was the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll different from other dolls?
