1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W's 3

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia</ENAMEX>'s Plane is Missing!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PACIFIC OCEAN</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July, 1937</TIMEX>)-A famous pilot and her plane are missing! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia</ENAMEX> is the lady's name.  She was last heard from as she flew over the ocean. 
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia</ENAMEX> was flying around the world. She was trying to set a record.  She wanted to be the first woman to fly around the world.
	She had a man pilot with her.  They had flown many miles before their plane was lost.
	People around the world know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia</ENAMEX>.  She was the first woman to do many things.  She flew across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX> all by herself.  She also flew across the country without making a stop.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia</ENAMEX> has been brave all her life.  She was given a medal for her courage.  It is called the Flying Cross.
	No one can say why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia</ENAMEX>'s plane is lost.  Maybe she got tired and stopped to rest.  It is hoped that she will be found safe on an island.

1.  Who is missing?

2.  What was she trying to do?

3.   When was her plane said to be missing?

4.  Where was she last known to be?

5.  Why was she given the Flying Cross?
