1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W's 3

Tooth Care Important for Animals, Too!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PHOENIX</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ARIZONA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1989</TIMEX>)-Most times you don't watch someone brush his or her teeth.  But a whole crowd came to see a patient get his teeth brushed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
	The patient was a dog named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>.  Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> showed the crowd how to take care of a pet's teeth.  Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> is a pet doctor called a vet.
	Most people don't think their pet's teeth matter.  But vets say that dogs and cats can get cavities, just like people do.  Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> says it is smart to brush the teeth of your pet at least once a week.
	Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> says that germs can enter through the mouth.  These germs can get into your pet's heart or liver.  They can make dogs and cats quite sick.
	Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> brushed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s teeth.  He put toothpaste on a special brush.  He rubbed the paste on the dog's teeth and gums.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> is used to this.  He didn't even mind.
	After the brushing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> got a reward.  He got a biscuit to chew.

1.  Who is a vet?

2.  What was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s reward?

3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> get the reward?

4.  Where did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> live?

5.  Why are germs bad?
