1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> Become Partners



	(WESTERN <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK STATE</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November, 1856</TIMEX>) - Two former enemies have joined together to make sewing machines.

	Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias Howe</ENAMEX> made the first sewing machine.  His idea was to make a machine that could use a needle and thread to quickly sew clothes.  The same task by hand would take hours.

	For a long time, no one believed the sewing machine really worked.  In fact, a man carried one around in a wagon and charged people <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 cents</NUMEX> just to look at it.

	In time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Singer</ENAMEX> saw one of these machines.  He started to make his own and sell them.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> got angry and took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> to court.  The court said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> had to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> money to use his designs.

	Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> have become partners.  Their dream is to make so many sewing machines that each home will have one.  They see a great need for families to be able to make and repair their own clothes.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> say that, in 15 years, they will be selling 1/2 million machines a year.



1. Who have become partners?



2. What do they make?



3. When do they think they can sell 1/2 million sewing machines a year?



4. Where did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> got angry?



5. Why is the sewing machine useful?

