1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> Develops Assembly Line



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">DETROIT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MICHIGAN</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April, 1913</TIMEX>) - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ford</ENAMEX> is once again surprising the world with a bright idea. 

	You may know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> built his first automobile back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890's</TIMEX>.  His horseless carriage quickly became a hit with the public.  Since then, he has become a rich man building autos by the thousands.

	Still, the demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX>'s cars keeps growing.  At one point, it seemed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX>'s workers would never keep up with the orders.  After giving the problem some thought, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> came up with an idea.

	In order to make more cars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> thought they must be made faster.  So he now has each worker do only one task all day.  One man just puts bolts on the cars.  Another man tightens the bolts.

The parts move past the workers on a belt.  This belt is a certain height so that no one has to bend over and waste time.

This new way of making cars is called an assembly line.  Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> believes his company will make millions of cars a year, instead of thousands.







1. Who developed the first assembly line?



2. What was another name for an automobile or car?



3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> make his first auto?



4.  Where are the parts when they move past the workers?



5.  Why does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> think his company will make millions of cars a year?

