1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> Wins First World Series!



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BOSTON, MASS.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 13, 1903</TIMEX>) - The world of baseball has a new event and a new champion.  The first World Series has just been completed.  After a long and exciting series of games, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> team has beaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>.

	The World Series is expected to become a yearly event.  The best team from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> will play the best team from the newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX>.

	It comes as a surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>.  Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> team had more desire to win because they played the final game in their home town.  A huge crowd was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Huntington Avenue</ENAMEX> ball field to cheer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>.

	The World Series winner is the team that wins the best of eight games.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> won five games to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>'s three.  Many fans say that the turning point was the second game which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> won by a score of 3-0.  From that point on, they played like true champions.

	The hero of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> team is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cy Young</ENAMEX>.  He won two of the games for his team with his great pitching.



1. Who played in the first World Series?



2.  What are the names of the two baseball leagues?



3.  When was the turning point for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX>?



4.  Where was the final World Series game played?



5.  Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cy Young</ENAMEX> the hero of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> team?

