1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> Becomes 50th State



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">HONOLULU</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">HAWAII</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 21, 1959</TIMEX>) Eight islands in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> have become our 50th state.  The islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> were given the rights of statehood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> has been trying to become a state since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, It has almost 600,000 people.  Because it is so beautiful, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX>'s nickname is "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise of the Pacific</ENAMEX>."

	President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Eisenhower</ENAMEX> displayed a new flag design.  It has nine rows.  Some have six stars each and others have five stars.  This is the 20th time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> has had a new flag.

	This is the second time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that a new state has been added.  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> became the 49th state.  It was the first new state since <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> has a lot of oil underground.  It is the largest state with the fewest number of people.

	Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> border any of the other states.  Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, they have been territories of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.  That means the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> owned them, but the people could not vote or have certain other rights.  Now <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> will be treated the same as all the other states.



1. Who displayed a new flag design?



2. What is the 50th state?



3. When was the last state added before <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>?



4. Where is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX>?



5. Why is it better to be a state than a territory?

