1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Palace for Shoppers Opens



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK CITY</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 20, 1862</TIMEX>) The best place to do all your holiday shopping this year is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart's Cast Iron Palace</ENAMEX>.  This new building is eight stories tall and is the biggest store in the world.  It is named for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.T. Stewart</ENAMEX>, the builder.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart's</ENAMEX> has more than 2,000 clerks ready to serve you.  Whether you need gloves, an umbrella, or a suitcase, you can find it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart's</ENAMEX>.

	This new kind of shopping place is called a department store.  It looks different on the outside as well as the inside.

	Stewart's Palace is made from a material called cast iron.  It is a very strong iron that can support a tall building.  On the ground floor are many huge windows.  Shoppers who are walking along the sidewalks can stroll past and look into the store.

	Inside, the store looks like a palace.  It contains a grand staircase and a glass roof which lets the sunshine enter.



1. Who built a new kind of store?



2.  What kind of store is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart's</ENAMEX>?



3.  When is a great time to shop at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart's</ENAMEX>?



4.  Where was this store built?



5.  Why is this a new kind of store?

