1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Tennis Queen Is Only 18



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LONDON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ENGLAND</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6,1974</TIMEX>) - All of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> is talking about the new queen of tennis.  Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Evert</ENAMEX> has won a big tournament in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> called Wimbledon.  She is only 18, but she has been playing tennis since she was four.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.  Her home is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX>.  She first was noticed three years ago when she showed she could beat older players who had more experience.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> is not as big or as strong as some of the other players.  In fact, as a youngster she was too weak to hit the tennis balls that landed on her left side.  She is right-handed. So her father, who is her coach, taught her to use both hands.  Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> hits those left-side balls with her two-hand backhand.

	By the time she was nine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> could beat any of her girlfriends at tennis.  Soon she was beating the boys in the neighborhood, too.  Her parents knew that she could be one of the best.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> always keeps her cool.  Even when she misses the ball, she doesn't get upset.  That's one reason why the crowds like to cheer for her.



1. Who is the new queen of tennis?



2. What is the name of the tournament she won?



3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> start playing tennis?



4.  Where does she live?



5.  Why do the crowds like to cheer for her?

