1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Hula Hoops Sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pole</ENAMEX>



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pole</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2, 1959</TIMEX>)  Sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, the latest fad will reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pole</ENAMEX>.  A shipment of hula hoops is expected to arrive any day.  The scientists who live there will probably use them to exercise and to keep warm.

	The hula hoop has been taking the world by storm.  This simple, round piece of plastic was first made in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Australia</ENAMEX>.  Two men took the idea.  They made a few changes and brought it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.

	In the past few months, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wham-O Company</ENAMEX> has sold 30 million hoops in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.  The price has dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.79</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 cents</NUMEX> per hoop.

	Adults seem to have trouble, but children catch on right away.  The idea is to see how long the hoop can stay in motion around your waist.  To keep it moving, you must swing your hips in a circle.  If the hoop starts to slip down your legs, just swing harder and faster to keep it from hitting the ground.



1. Who is about to receive a shipment of hula hoops?



2.  What company has sold 30 million hula hoops?



3.  When will hula hoops be sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pole</ENAMEX>?



4.  Where did the hula hoop start?



5.  Why do you think the price of hula hoops has dropped so much?

