1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Space Pioneers Don't Monkey Around

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28,1959</TIMEX>) - Two small monkeys have made a safe splashdown after their first trip into space.
	Scientists say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Able</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> seem healthy and glad to be back on the ground.  Their trip took them 1,700 miles through space at speeds reaching 10,000 miles per hour.
	These two monkeys are space pioneers who took the place of people.  In this way, scientists can study how space travel affects living creatures.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Able</ENAMEX> weighs seven pounds, and tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> weighs just one pound.  Both of them have small, metal pieces placed near their brains.  In theirs spacecraft, they were wired to boxes so scientists could tell how they act in space.  They measured their heartbeat, breathing, and other signs of life.
	Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX> sent a dog named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laika</ENAMEX> into space.  When her spacecraft returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laika</ENAMEX> was dead.  Many more space tests will have to be made before the first person can be safely sent.

1. Who went into space and came back safely?

2. What kind of animals are they?

3. When did they safely land back on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>?

4. Where did scientists place small metal parts?

5. Why are animals sent into space?
