1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Women in Charge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>





(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">EL PASO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TEXAS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 27, 1989</TIMEX>) - The city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Paso</ENAMEX> has chosen its first woman to be mayor.  Her name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzie Azar</ENAMEX>.  She is a pilot and teaches flying.  She has also been a member of the city council for four years.

	Now the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> has women mayors in six of its largest cities.  The other cities are <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dallas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Galveston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX>.

 	It is rare to have women as mayors.  In fact, only 12 out of each 100 cities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> have women in the top job.

	But <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> has always been known for its strong women.  More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> women were running farms and working on their ranches.  They have always had to do many of the chores that men do.  So it is no surprise that they would also want to be active in government.

	Another woman has said she would like to run for the office of governor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>.  All over the state, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> women are helping to decide how things will get done.



1. Who is the first woman mayor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Paso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>?



2.  What other cities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> have women mayors?



3.  When was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzie Azar</ENAMEX> elected mayor?



4.  Where did she serve for four years before becoming mayor?



5.  Why have <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> women always been strong?

