1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Blind and Deaf Student Finishes College



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radcliffe College</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1, 1904</TIMEX>) - A lady who is both blind and deaf completed college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  Her name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Keller</ENAMEX>.  She has finished all her courses at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radcliffe College</ENAMEX>.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> talks with people by touching them.  She reads special books for the blind.  The letters in these textbooks have been turned into a series of bumps which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> feels.  She writes her lessons using a special typewriter.

	Although she cannot see or hear, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> gets good grades.  She always attends classes with her special friend, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Sullivan</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> listens to the teachers.  She tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> what they are saying.  She does this by touching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>'s hand and using a code they both understand.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX>.  As a baby, she could see and hear.  When she was two years old, she became very ill.  The disease caused her to lose her sight and hearing.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> is a teacher who was hired to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> get along in the world.

	<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> wrote a book called The Story of My Life.







1. Who is a deaf and blind student who finished college?



2.  What is the name of her special friend?



3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> lose her sight and hearing?



4. Where did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> go to college?



5. Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> able to understand her teachers?

