1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Mayor Drives <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>'s First Subway Train



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 27, 1904</TIMEX>) - A train that runs underground made its first trip through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  The train is called a subway.  Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClellan</ENAMEX> was there to drive the first train.

	Above the ground, people blew tin whistles and fired guns.  As the mayor made his way through the lighted tunnels, 15,000 guests applauded.  The public is invited to take rides starting at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 o'clock tonight</TIMEX>.

	The subway has olive green cars. They stop at a series of white subway station buildings.  At each station, the train drops off and takes on passengers.  The train rides quietly on steel rails.

	Now people will be able to get to work faster.  As more stations are added, they will be able to reach almost any place in the city.

	It took four years to build this subway.  There is another one in the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston</ENAMEX> that has been in use for a few years.

	The world's oldest subway is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">London</ENAMEX>.  It was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>.



1.  Who drove the first <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX> subway?



2.  What is a subway?



3.  When was the world's first subway built?



4.  Where is another city in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> with a subway?



5. Why is the subway useful?

