1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Quints Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Dakota</ENAMEX>!



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ABERDEEN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S.D.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 14, 1963</TIMEX>) - Mr. and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX> became parents <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.  They have a healthy, new baby boy ... and a boy ... and a boy ... and a boy ... and a girl.  They had five babies!  The babies are called quints, which means five.

	Quints are quite rare.  They happen only once in every 85 million births.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX> quints are the first ones born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> that have lived.  Those born in the past lived only hours or days.  Most quints are so tiny that their hearts and lungs are not big enough to keep them alive.

	The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischers</ENAMEX> are surprised to have so many babies.  They need some time to think about names for their children.  Many people are sending them clothes and toys.

	There is another famous set of quints in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.  Five baby girls were born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28, 1934</TIMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX> family.  Their names are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecile</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yvonne</ENAMEX>.

	When four babies are born at once, they are called quads.  Three makes triplets, and two are twins.



1.  Who became parents of quints on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 14</TIMEX>?



2.  What does "quint" mean?



3.  When were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX> quints born?



4.  Where do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX> quints live?



5.  Why do so few quints live?

