1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



Young Chinese Artist Has Show in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>



	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 1989</TIMEX>) - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Yani</ENAMEX> is 14 years old and lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX>.  She loves to paint and has finished about 6,000 pictures in her life.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX>'s art is popular in her native land.  Now she has become famous in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> she has her own art show at a well-known museum in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX> is the youngest person to ever receive this honor.  She was allowed to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> for this big event.  While she is here she wants to see our museums.  She also wants to eat fried chicken.

	Her favorite subjects to paint are animals.  Right now, she is painting monkeys.  Her parents encourage her to use her talent.  Each day she rises early and starts to paint.  She goes to school, then returns home in the afternoon and paints some more.  She has more classes at night, but she still finds a little time for art before bed.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX> started to paint at age 2 1/2.  When she was a little girl, her art teacher didn't like her paintings.  This upset <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX>.  Now she paints what she likes and doesn't care what people think.



1. Who is the youngest person to have her own art show in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>?



2.  What does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX> like to paint?



3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX> begin to paint?



4.  Where does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX> live?



5.  Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang</ENAMEX> once get upset?

