1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s - 5



<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Swimmer Wins Seven Gold Medals!







	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MUNICH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GERMANY</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 4, 1972</TIMEX>) - A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> swimmer has won seven gold medals at the Olympics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Spitz</ENAMEX> has set a world record for winning.  He is 22 years old and lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>.

	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> won each swimming event he entered at the Olympics.  The events are the  100- and 200-meter freestyle, the 100- and 200-meter butterfly stroke, and three different relay races with his team.

	The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> has had a second big win at these games.  One of its team members has won the gold medal in the marathon.  His name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Shorter</ENAMEX>.  It is the first time someone from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> has won this race since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>.

	A marathon is a running race that lasts 26 miles.  Very few runners are able to compete in this race.  It takes three or four hours to finish the course.

	There is one big disappointment at this year's Olympics.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> lost the gold medal in basketball to the team from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX>.  This is the first time the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> has not won this event.



1. Who has won seven gold medals?



2. What other big event did the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> win?



3. When was the last time the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> won the gold medal in a marathon?



4. Where were these Olympic games held?



5. Why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> disappointed?

