1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Storybook Person Found Alive!

   (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ENGLAND</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June, 1989</TIMEX>) - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Robin</ENAMEX> is alive and well.  He lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX>.  He is the same person that you read about in the book, Winnie the Pooh.
   As a boy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> lived in a pretty home called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cotchfield Farm</ENAMEX>.  When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> was three years old, his father wrote a poem about him.  The poem was printed in a magazine for others to read.   
   Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> then wrote a book.  He made up a fairy tale land where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> lived.  His friends were animals.  There was a bear called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie the Pooh</ENAMEX>.  There was also an owl and a young pig, called a piglet.  All the animals were stuffed toys that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> owned.  Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> made them come to life with his words.  The places in the story were all near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cotchfield Farm</ENAMEX>. 
   Winnie the Pooh was written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>.  Children still love to read about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Robin</ENAMEX> and his animal friends.  Most people don't know he is a real person who is grown now.  He has written two books of his own.  They tell what it is like to be famous.

1. Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Robin</ENAMEX>?

2. What did Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> do when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> was three years old?

3.  When was Winnie the Pooh written?

4.  Where did young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> live?

5.  Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> write two books of his own?
