1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Owens Wins 4th Gold Medal!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MUNICH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GERMANY</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>) - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Owens</ENAMEX> is the fastest man in the world.  He runs and wins for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> team.  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> won his fourth gold medal in the Olympics.
	Each time he wins a medal, it is placed around his neck.  A band plays the "Star-Spangled Banner."
	This is not the first time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> has shown his speed.  A few years ago, he broke five world records.  In fact, he did this in one hour.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>'s future was not always bright.  As a boy, he was quite sick and weak.  Some winters, he could not go to school.  All he could do was stay in bed.
	In high school, he began to train.  He could not run after school because he had a job.  So he would get up early and run.  At first, he just wanted to build his strength.  Later, he began to race against others.
	The sick, young boy grew into a strong man.  Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>'s name will be known around the world.  He has earned a place in sports history.


1.  Who is the fastest man in the world?

2.  What music is played when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> wins a gold medal?

3.  When did he begin to train?

4.  Where did he win four medals?

5.  Why was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>'s future not bright at one time?
