1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Girl Swims to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX>!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RUSSIA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July, 1987</TIMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, a girl named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne Cox</ENAMEX> swam from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX>!  She made the trip in two hours and six minutes.
 	If you look at a map, you may be puzzled.  It looks like a long way between the two countries.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX> took a shortcut. She swam across a place called the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bering Strait</ENAMEX>.  She left from an island in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>. She swam to an island in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX>.  The trip was five miles long. 
	To get ready for this swim, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX> swam miles each day in ice-cold water. The water in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bering Strait</ENAMEX> is 38 degrees. Most people would freeze to death in it. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX> is trained to do well in icy water. 
	During her swim, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX> had company.  Her coach and others rode alongside her in a small boat.  They were ready to help if she needed it.
	All went well for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX>.  When she was finished, some Russians were waiting to greet her.  "This is the hardest thing I've ever done," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX>.

1. Who swam from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX>?

2. What did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX> do to get ready for her swim?

3.  When did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX> make this swim?

4.  Where did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX> start her swim?

5.  Why did her coach go with her?
