1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Sailor Spends 4 Years on Island

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SCOTLAND</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 1709</TIMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX>, a ship pulled up to shore.  On board was a sailor with a strange tale to tell.  The man's name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Selkirk</ENAMEX>.  He says he lived alone on an island for four years and four months. 
	The tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX> starts almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>.  He was a sailor on board a ship that leaked.  The ship stopped at an island to be fixed.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX> said he would not sail on a leaking ship.  So the ship sailed without him. 
	All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX> had were his clothes, bedding, books, compass, knife, and tools.  He had enough food for two meals.  He made a fire from some gunpowder. 
	Then he explored the island.  It was about 12 miles long.  Soon he found all the food he needed.  He ate plums, crayfish, peppers, and turnips.  He lived in a cave.
	Once, pirates came ashore but didn't find him.  At long last, a friendly ship saw his campfire.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX> was rescued on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 12</TIMEX>.  This time, he was happy to get on the ship.

1. Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Selkirk</ENAMEX>?

2. What did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX> eat on the island?

3.  When was he rescued?

4.  Where did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX> live on the island?

5. Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX> stay on the island?
