1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Day of Thanks To Be Held

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PLYMOUTH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MASSACHUSETTS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July, 1623</TIMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>, a day of thanks will be held.  On that day, people will eat a great feast.  They will be thankful for the rains that made a good crop.
	The first day of thanks was held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1621</TIMEX>.  The people, called Pilgrims, gave thanks for their lives.  They had come to this new land from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1620</TIMEX>.  The first <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> was a long, hard one.  Many men, women, and children died.
	By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>, only 55 Pilgrims were left.  They were very sad.  An Indian named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squanto</ENAMEX> came to help them.  He gave them seeds and showed them how to grow a food called corn.
	By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>, the Pilgrims had enough food for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>.  They thought it would be nice to have a party.  They asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squanto</ENAMEX> to come and bring his friends.
	For three days, the Pilgrims cooked deer, turkeys, ducks, and fish.  They baked bread.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squanto</ENAMEX> showed them how to make pudding from corn.
	Then the Pilgrims and the Indians ate and played games.  "This is fun," they said.  "We'll hold a day of thanks each year."

1. Who helped the Pilgrims?

2. What did they eat on the first day of thanks?

3.  When was the first day of thanks held?

4.  Where did the Pilgrims live before coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>?

5. Why were the Pilgrims sad?
