1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Sea World Welcomes New Baby!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORLANDO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">FLORIDA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September, 1985</TIMEX>) - A six-foot-long baby was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>.  Her name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Shamu</ENAMEX>.  She is a killer whale.  She was born in a sea animal park called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX>.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Shamu</ENAMEX>'s mother is named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kandu</ENAMEX>.  Each year, thousands of people come to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX> to see her do tricks. Someday, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Shamu</ENAMEX> will join her mother's act.  She has already learned to swim by watching her mother.
	Not much is known about baby killer whales.  The workers at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX> will watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Shamu</ENAMEX> each day and make notes.  She could grow to be 20 feet long and weigh more than 10,000 pounds.  She will be a fast swimmer like other killer whales.
	<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baby Shamu</ENAMEX> will be the first killer whale to grow up with people.  The other killer whales at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX> grew up in the ocean.  Then they were captured.  They were brought to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX> to be trained and studied.

1. Who had a baby at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX>?

2.  What is the baby's name?

3.  When was the baby born?

4.  Where do these sea animals live?

5. Why is this baby important?
