1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Light Bulb Burns for 78 Years!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LIVERMORE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CALIFORNIA</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the light bulb is 100 years old. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1879</TIMEX>, people used candles or oil lamps.
	Most light bulbs are used only a few hours a day.  They last a year or two.  But a bulb in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Livermore</ENAMEX> has been shining day and night since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>!  No one can explain why it hasn't burned out.
	This light bulb is in the fire station.  It was hand-blown years ago by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shelby Company</ENAMEX>.
	A switch is by the light.  But no one ever uses it.  The light has been out only twice.  The first time was when the fire station moved to a new building.  The other time was for a week.  Some work had to be done, and the power was turned off.
	It is said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Livermore</ENAMEX> light bulb should have been changed more than 800 times by now.  For all we know, it could last 78 more years!



1. Who made the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Livermore</ENAMEX> light bulb?

2. What is strange about this light?

3.  When was the first light bulb made?

4.  Where is the longest-lasting light bulb?

5. Why doesn't the light bulb burn out?
