1989 Remedia Publications, Comprehension/5W’s2

Volcano Wipes Out Town!

	(<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ITALY</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 30, A.D. 79</TIMEX>) - A large volcano exploded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.  Most of the people who lived in the nearby town have died.
	A teenage boy named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pliny</ENAMEX> escaped. He has many stories to tell.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pliny</ENAMEX> was visiting his uncle.  It was morning.  He was eating breakfast.  All at once, his plate shook.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pliny</ENAMEX> looked out the window.  A large, white cloud was in the sky.  Then the cloud turned black.  The whole room began to shake.
	"Run for your life," he heard people yell.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pliny</ENAMEX> ran down to the sea.  He jumped on a boat as it pulled away from the shore.
	He looked back and saw an awful sight.  Hot ashes flew through the air and burned the people.  The people fell to the ground before they could reach the cool water.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pliny</ENAMEX>'s boat arrived safely at a village.  Later, a team of workers went back to offer help.  They say that the whole town is under 20 feet of ashes.  No one can be found alive.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pliny</ENAMEX> is writing down what he saw.  People in the future will read about this event.

1. Who was on a visit to his uncle?

2. What did he see out the window?

3.  When did this story happen?

4.  Where is the town now?

5. Why did the people die?
